annualreviews.org 2019-11-03

# Privacy Policy

Last Updated: May 5, 2018

Annual Reviews is firmly committed to protecting the privacy of personal information provided by those visiting and interacting with our organization online. The following discloses our policies for information gathering and dissemination on this website.

#### Website Usage Information Collected

We may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and administer our website. We use cookies and we associate Institutional IP addresses with their institutions only for the purposes of access control and usage of the Annual Reviews site. We also track the quantity of traffic to the various areas of our site. Annual Reviews tracks how often each page is visited. This helps us to maintain a useful and informative website. Annual Reviews uses Google Analytics. You can control any personal information Google collects via Google’s Privacy controls (<https://privacy.google.com/take-control.html>). Annual Reviews receives no personal information from Google Analytics.

#### Cookies and How We Use Them

Cookies are unique identifiers that we transfer to your device to enable our systems to recognize your device and to provide features such as authentication.

We also use cookies for additional purposes, including:

  * Identifying you when you sign-in to our site. This allows us to provide you with personalized features and access to your subscribed/purchased content. You can view subscribed features and purchased content in your Account Profile.
  * Keeping track of items stored in your shopping basket and facilitating checkout.
  * Conducting research and diagnostics to improve Annual Reviews' products and services.
  * Preventing fraudulent activity.
  * Improving security.

If you do not accept the use of Cookies from www.annualreviews.org, the website will be non-functional.

#### Personal Information Collected

The types of personal information collected by Annual Reviews depends on how you use or access our products and online features, and may include:

  * Contact details, such as your name, email address, postal address and telephone number;
  * Educational or professional information such as affiliation, field of study, current position and your interests;
  * Account login credentials (usernames and passwords);
  * Payment information (credit or debit card number);
  * Social network or social media credentials;
  * Communication consent and preferences, such as e-TOC alerts or email marketing.

#### How We Use Your Information

##### Annual Reviews Email Practices

We use customer contact information to send email order confirmations, necessary follow-up information, as well as information about Annual Reviews and our product offerings. If you do not wish to receive emails, please let us know by accessing the User Preference Center or by calling, emailing, or writing to us. Our contact information is also provided below.

If you consent to receive marketing communications from us, we will use your personal data to send you company news, promotional information about our products, and newsletters. You may remove your name from our mailing lists at any time, or change your email address, or preferences, by accessing our User Preference Center or by calling, emailing, or writing to us. You may also “opt-out” or unsubscribe from within the communications you receive from us. You can manage your automated table of contents (eTOC) and citation alerts when you register and by updating your account profile.

Annual Reviews also publishes [_Knowable Magazine_](https://www.knowablemagazine.org/ "Knowable Magazine by Annual Reviews"), which produces a weekly e-newsletter. From the _Knowable Magazine_ website, you can learn more about [_Knowable Magazine’s_ privacy policy](https://www.knowablemagazine.org/page/privacy-policy "Knowable Magazine privacy policy") and manage your email preferences directly.

To report an incident of unsolicited email (spam), or any other concerns, please email [marketing@annualreviews.org](mailto:marketing@annualreviews.org). Our full contact information is provided below.

##### Annual Reviews Direct Mail Practices

If you supply us with your postal address, you could receive periodic mailings that may be of legitimate interest to you about our products, services, or upcoming events. If you do not want to receive such mailings, please let us know by calling us, emailing us, or writing us using the contact information provided below.

##### Annual Reviews Surveys

We may conduct occasional online surveys via our website or via email. These surveys are entirely voluntary, and you can easily decline to participate. Participating in an online survey does not automatically add your name to subscriber lists for Annual Reviews mailings of any kind.

##### Annual Reviews Telephone Practices

Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers when ordering may receive calls from us regarding the orders they have placed.

##### No Ad Servers

We have no relationships with any ad server companies.

##### Links

This site contains links to the websites of other organizations. Annual Reviews is not responsible for the privacy practices or the changing content of such websites. For more information, please review the privacy policies of these sites as well.

##### Sharing of Information

We share your personal information as necessary to complete a transaction or provide a service that you have requested or authorized.

We may share your personal information with our service providers, including credit card processors, email service providers, mailing houses, shipping agents and website platform service providers.

Annual Reviews offers online journal subscriptions to individual users and institutions. If users access content through an institution-sponsored subscription, their anonymous article usage is counted and aggregated into institutional usage metrics for the purposes of usage analysis and subscription management.

##### Access to, Accuracy and Deletion of Your Information

Registered users may access their account information and make corrections or updates upon log in at any time. The accuracy of such information is solely the responsibility of the user.

If you request to deactivate your account or delete your personal information, Annual Reviews will fulfill your request, but some personal information may persist in backup copies for a certain period of time or may be retained as necessary for legitimate business purposes or to comply with legal or audit obligations.

#####  Cross-border Transfer of Your Information

Your personal information may be transferred to and stored in servers and facilities located in your region or another country. We take steps to ensure that the information continues to be protected wherever it is located.

#### Policy Modifications

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If/when Annual Reviews changes its policies on the collection or use of personal information, or we begin to use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice, we will state our revised policies with an updated revision date here.

If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should review our privacy policy periodically. Users may decline to permit new uses of their personal information (or can revise their prior permissions) by calling us, emailing us, or writing us via the contact information provided in this policy. 

#### How to Contact Annual Reviews About Information Privacy

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, the information collected from you online, or our information-privacy practices on this website, please contact:

Annual Reviews  
Attn Paul Calvi, Director of IT and Data Protection Officer  
4139 El Camino Way  
Palo Alto, CA 94306 USA  
650.493.4400
